“Episode 10”
《第10集》
"3 days later"
「3天后」
Is there a reason?
有理由吗？
Were you afraid that I might suddenly hug you again?
你是不是害怕我会突然再次拥抱你？
Pay homage to Emperor Zong and the Princess
瞻仰宗皇及公主
Thank you so much for traveling this far.
非常感谢您跑这么远。
thank you for the invitation.
感谢你的邀请。
We feel very honored.
我们感到非常荣幸。
When given the chance
当有机会时
Join the Festival Annual Incense
参加节日 年香
Please sit down.
请坐下。
thank you
谢谢
The young master of the Wu family has arrived.
吴家少爷来了。
My name is Wu Suo Mo from Wu Family.
我叫吴所莫，来自吴家。
I would like to pay tribute to you and your princess.
我谨向您和您的公主致敬。
Forgive me for being late.
很抱歉，我来晚了。
It's not too late. You came just in time.
还不算太晚，你来得正是时候。
Please sit down.
请坐下。
The smell is so unique.
气味是如此独特。
very fragrant
很香
Only the Zhong family could produce it.
只有钟家才能制作。
I heard that it is famous for its scent. many of them
听说它以香味闻名。 许多人
There's nothing better than seeing it with your own eyes.
没有什么比亲眼所见更好的了。
Incense Festival
香祭
It's getting bigger every year
每年都在变大
Look at this acting.
看看这演技
How much incense should I burn?
应该烧多少香？
Only then will people remember.
只有这样，人们才会记住。
Besides, they were the Zhong family.
更何况，他们还是钟家。
There is no shortage of perfume.
香水是不缺的。
really
真的
Besides perfume
除了香水
Tea and snacks on the table
桌上的茶和点心
It smells good too.
味道也很好闻。
Be sure to try it.
一定要尝试一下。
First, I invite you.
首先，我邀请你。
This age is already
这个年纪已经
still stubborn
仍然固执
What do you say?
你怎么说？
There is nothing.
没有什么。
- Please drink. - Please.
-请喝酒 。-请。
Have you tracked down the source yet?
你查到源头了吗？
I'll tell my subordinates to check again.
我会吩咐下属再检查一下。
Incense used at this year’s Incense Festival
今年香祭所用的香
It's definitely a Zen perfume.
这绝对是一款禅宗香水。
charming
迷人
Just... sir, please...
只是……先生，请……
Should we do this?
我们应该这样做吗？
If one day my master finds out
如果有一天我的主人发现了
I'm worried it might be unfair.
我担心这可能不公平。
When in doubt
有疑问时
Just kill her.
杀了她就行了。
It doesn't have to be handled this way.
不必这样处理。
The Mu family is already in trouble.
穆家已经陷入困境了。
I won't do anything to her.
我不会对她做任何事。
I have a plan.
我有个计划。
Father's body gradually weakens
父亲的身体 逐渐衰弱
Therefore he had no influence. in my decision
所以他没有影响力。 在我的决定中
I know you're hesitant.
我知道你在犹豫。
Because of past events
因为过去的事件
After all, she was from the Mu family.
毕竟 她是慕家的人。
If she finds out...
如果她发现的话……
Then never let her know.
那就永远不要让她知道。
Sir, I can assure you of this matter.
先生，这件事我可以向你保证。
However, during ancestral rites
然而，在祭祀祖先的时候
I see clearly
我看清楚了
She was willing to give up her life for that big man.
为了那个大男人，她愿意放弃自己的生命。
I feel sorry for that person...
我为那个人感到难过...
“I didn’t notice last time.”
“我上次没注意到。”
“But enough to notice.”
“但足以引起注意。”
“They were very explicit.”
“他们非常明确。”
“Does he feel guilty?”
“他感到内疚吗？”
"예"
“예”
“His arrow almost took my life.”
“他的箭差点要了我的命。”
“Because I’m the only one who knows.”
“因为我是唯一知道的人。”
“So I can use this to threaten him.”
“所以我可以用这个来威胁他。”
Please put down your chopsticks.
请放下筷子。
great.
伟大的。
When drinking tea...
喝茶的时候...
We also eat dessert together
我们还一起吃甜点
The following activities are familiar to everyone.
以下活动是大家都熟悉的。
It is a test of scent.
这是对气味的考验。
The rules remain the same.
规则保持不变。
A person who answers ingredients accurately
准确回答成分的人
will be the first winner
将成为第一个获胜者
It's balsa wood.
这是轻木。
There is a homemade incense stick under your feet.
脚下有一炷自制的香。
It has properties that help prevent bubonic plague.
它具有有助于预防鼠疫的特性。
refresh
刷新
And treats swelling and pain.
并治疗肿胀和疼痛。
Because now is an important time.
因为现在是一个重要的时刻。
Can you give a gift to a traveling guest?
可以给旅行的客人送礼物吗？
I came a long way to see Ya Jiayin.
我千里迢迢赶来见雅佳音。
passed down through generations
代代相传
Can I get it or not?
我能拿到还是不能拿到？
Master Wooyoung, you may not know.
宇荣大师，你可能不知道。
The main ingredient is blood amber.
主要成分是血琥珀。
And quality pieces are very difficult to find.
而且高质量的作品很难找到。
Moreover, Jiayin Pill is
而且，加银丸是
Originally brought here, it was used to treat hallucinations.
最初被带到这里来， 是用来治疗幻觉的。
Therefore, we must keep it. Please leave it to those who need it.
因此，我们必须保留它。 请留给有需要的人。
Not considered as festival eligible
不被视为 符合节日资格
sorry. I don't know about this.
对不起。我不知道这个。
I heard this scent is hard to find.
听说这个香味很难找。
So I'd like to take a look.
所以我想看一下。
I'll have to think about it more carefully.
我得更仔细地考虑一下。
His Majesty Zhong almost never makes his own perfume.
钟皇几乎从不 自己制作香水。
And the scent of balsa wood
还有轻木的香气
It is difficult to find it in the market.
在市场上很难找到它。
yes...
是的...
So let's get started.
那么让我们开始吧。
If everyone can, guess the ingredients correctly
如果每个人都能 猜对成分
The person with the most correct answers
回答最正确的人
will be a winner
将成为赢家
Why does it smell so familiar?
为什么闻起来这么熟悉？
It is a Zen perfume. Isn't this normal?
这是一款禅宗香水。 这不是很正常吗？
Should I try this scent like that?
我应该尝试一下这样的香味吗？
Are you rather rude?
你是不是比较粗鲁？
It smells different.
闻起来不一样。
I feel more refreshed and comfortable.
我感觉更加清爽和舒适。
The smell is so unique. A true Zen perfume
气味是如此独特。 真正的禅宗香水
So why was this put to the test?
那么为什么要对此进行测试呢？
That's it.
就是这样。
“What’s missing?”
“少了什么东西？”
"i know."
“我知道。”
Please help me do the right thing.
请帮助我做正确的事。
Teacher, please enjoy. First with incense
老师请欣赏。 先上香
I'm going to the bathroom.
我要去卫生间。
To not disturb you.
为了不打扰你。
Brother Chi, plum wine is sweet and smooth.
池兄，梅酒甘甜滑爽。
It tastes better than the one boiled in the garden.
比花园里煮的好吃。
Maybe you're not in a good mood.
也许你心情不太好。
So invite them over for a drink and a chat.
所以请他们过来喝一杯、聊聊。
But you seem to be in a very good mood.
但你看起来心情很好。
Why should I be angry?
我为什么要生气？
Haven't you heard the music?
你没听过音乐吗？
The sound of drums coming from the main hall
鼓声从大殿中传来
It arrived at my house.
它到达了我家。
But all we can do is sit here and drink.
但我们能做的就是坐在这里喝酒。
Because we weren't invited to the festival.
因为我们没有被邀请参加这个节日。
People attending the incense festival
参加香祭的人们
They made a deal with the Zhong family.
他们和钟家做了一笔交易。
We women need to be in our backyards.
我们女人需要在我们的后院。
Who said it?
谁说的？
As we spoke, Hua Qian was attending the event.
我们谈话时，华谦正在参加活动。
She is married to Mr. Yai.
她嫁给了Yai先生。
It is normal to have to go to work.
必须去上班是正常的。
We are the chief's daughters.
我们是酋长的女儿。
Why was she so lucky?
为什么她这么幸运？
She always got what she wanted.
她总能得到她想要的。
She is different from us.
她与我们不同。
Her father is a deacon.
她的父亲是一名执事。
We all serve the Zhong family.
我们都是为钟家服务的。
How are they different?
它们有何不同？
Besides, a woman like her is a playboy.
何况，像她这样的女人，也是个花花公子。
He is not worthy of the man she loves.
他配不上她爱的男人。
Madame Chao
赵女士
She already drank too much.
她已经喝太多了。
And he continued speaking while drunk.
然后他就喝醉了继续说话。
Yes, I'm drunk.
是的，我醉了。
This scent makes me drunk.
这香味让我醉了。
Plum wine made me drunk.
梅酒让我醉了。
Too much time has passed.
已经过去太多时间了。
I should go back and rest first.
我该回去休息了。
Please take care of Brother Qi.
请照顾齐哥哥。
Lady, aren’t you going to the bathroom?
小姐，你不去洗手间吗？
Why did we come here?
我们为什么来这里？
It's quiet here. I want to breathe air.
这里很安静。我想呼吸空气。
There's still an hour left in the festival .
距离节日 还有一个小时。
Another scent test.
又一个气味测试。
Not very interesting.
不是很有趣。
I'll be back soon. Near the end of the festival
我很快回来。 临近节日尾声
Why was the landlady alone?
为何房东太太孤身一人？
“Why did he follow me?”
“他为什么跟着我？”
chenzi
陈子
What wind brought Mr. Wu here?
是什么风把吴先生吹到这里来的？
I really want to come. thank you
我真的很想来。谢谢
But I didn't expect that.
但我没想到会这样。
It's different from what was just rumored
和刚刚传闻的不一样
I don't think so
我不这么认为
The young master will study a lot of information.
小少爷会研究很多资料。
Before leaving for this trip to Hwangcheong
在出发前往黄清之前
This includes studying myself.
这包括学习我自己。
You are the most talented woman in this city.
你是这个城市最有才华的女人。
So I guess I heard that too. It's definitely about you.
所以我想我也听到了。 这绝对是关于你的。
Young Master praises me so much.
少爷对我赞不绝口。
I was out longer than I should have been.
我出去的时间比应有的时间要长。
Please come back first.
请先回来。
I heard about your marriage. your happiness
我听说了你结婚的事。 你的幸福
This is something that many people envy.
这是很多人羡慕的事情。
But now you two
但现在你们两个
Do they have a cold attitude towards each other?
他们对彼此的态度是否冷淡？
"What happen"
“发生什么事”
“In my past life, I was the one who approached him first.”
“前世， 我是第一个接近他的人。”
“ Zhong Yeran and Mu Yao to help with the breakup .”
“钟野然和慕瑶帮忙分手。”
“Why is he taking the initiative now?”
“他怎么现在主动了？”
garage suomu
车库索姆
You were very clever in finding this place.
你很聪明，找到了这个地方。
But that's not the case. Do I have bad manners?
但事实并非如此。 我有没有礼貌吗？
You came dressed like this
你穿成这样来了
At night
晚上
Wu Suo Mo, why did you decide to hide here?
无所魔， 你为什么要躲在这里？
What kind of person am I?
我是一个什么样的人？
what's the problem?
有什么问题？
You agreed to cooperate with me.
你同意与我合作。
Why did you turn your back on me?
你为什么背弃我？
What did we agree on?
我们在什么方面达成了一致？
He said he would take Mu Yao somewhere else.
他说要带慕瑶去别的地方。
Then I will rule over Zong Yeran.
那么我就统治宗野然了。
But don't you accept it now?
但现在你不接受吗？
Don't test me.
别考验我。
Otherwise, we will notify the authorities immediately.
否则，我们将立即通知当局。
And tell them you are behind it all.
并告诉他们 你是这一切的幕后黑手。
Please let me know.
请告诉我。
If I remember correctly
如果我没记错的话
The entire family was arrested.
全家人都 被捕了。
and was imprisoned
并被监禁
You came at just the right time.
你来得正是时候。
We'll give you some useful information.
我们将为您提供一些有用的信息。
Tomorrow I will go on a trip.
明天我要去旅行。
Leave the city via Donghuang Mountain.
出城经东黄山。
Therefore, you must hurry.
因此，你必须抓紧时间。
Let's wait and see if anyone believes it.
咱们拭目以待，看看有没有人相信。
An escaped prisoner like you
像你这样的逃犯
teacher...
老师...
Then you will raise Mu Yao.
那你就养育沐瑶吧。
Would you let Zhong treat your grandson?
你会让钟给你的孙子看病吗？
She doesn't want me.
她不要我了。
So I must let her go.
所以我必须放她走。
and me?
和我？
While he showed her mercy
当他向她怜悯时
My whole family was deported.
我的全家都被驱逐出境。
Before that, people from the Mu family
在此之前，穆家的人
killed or exiled
被杀或流放
It's not because of family, is it?
不是因为家庭的原因吧？
Karma overtook me.
业力超越了我。
Your family deserves it.
你的家人应得的。
how?
如何？
It was you who came up with this plan.
这个计划是你想出来的。
Now I can't blame anyone else.
现在我不能责怪任何人了。
You have canceled our contract.
你已经取消了我们的合同。
And call me back later
稍后给我回电话
So you can't leave me.
所以你不能离开我。
in other words ...
换句话说 ...
Do you want to be my girl?
你想成为我的女孩吗？
I am the smartest girl in town.
我是城里最聪明的女孩。
Wow, it's still number 1 in all fields of literature.
哇，它仍然是所有文学领域的第一名。
If you really betrayed me
如果你真的背叛了我
I won't let you go.
我不会让你走的。
Easy from Donghwangsan Mountain
距东皇山很近
don't forget it
别忘了
people of the wu family
吴家的人
It must be thousands of miles from here.
距离这里肯定有数千里。
You shouldn't show up right now in Hwangcheong.
你现在不应该出现在黄清。
Butler Hua is scheduled to be hanged tomorrow.
华管家定于明天被绞死。
Then your entire family will be deported.
那么你的全家都会被驱逐出境。
And he still came to introduce himself.
而且他还来自我介绍。
You want to threaten and seduce me.
你想威胁我、引诱我。
I was very impressed.
我印象非常深刻。
That you are so cold-blooded and selfish.
原来你这么冷血，这么自私。
but...
但...
I am not interested in used goods.
我对二手货不感兴趣。
teacher...
老师...
I'm afraid you might hesitate.
恐怕你会犹豫。
You just arrived
你刚到
So I sent someone to tell him. your inspector
于是我派人去告诉他。 你的检查员
When I meet that person after this
当我遇见那个人之后
Let's see if the person is interested.
让我们看看这个人是否感兴趣。
A foreigner like me
像我这样的外国人
Or maybe someone the authorities are targeting is more like you.
或者，也许当局针对的某个人 更像你。
I can't believe there are cowards like him.
我不敢相信还有像他这样的胆小鬼。
will try to threaten me
会试图威胁我
It's really stupid.
实在是太蠢了。
It's really ridiculous.
实在是太可笑了。
Did I say something wrong?
我说错什么了吗？
Married life is not so smooth.
婚姻生活并不是那么顺利。
sweet couple
甜蜜的一对
There may be unstable relationships.
可能会有不稳定的关系。
But the two truly respected each other.
但两人 确实互相尊重。
We can be together for a long time.
我们可以在一起很长一段时间。
Young Master, you are not married yet.
少爷，你还没结婚呢。
You probably won't understand.
你可能不会明白。
talk about marriage
谈论婚姻
I already have someone I like.
我已经有喜欢的人了
The maid standing behind me, that big man, caught my eye.
站在我身后的女仆， 那个大男人，引起了我的注意。
But he seemed to have feelings for her too.
但他似乎对她也有感情。
So that's what I'm afraid of
所以这就是我所害怕的
He won't let her go.
他不会让她走的。
Go and talk to that person yourself.
亲自去和那个人谈谈。
I can't make decisions for him.
我不能替他做决定。
Madam, don't you understand me?
夫人，您还不明白我的意思吗？
We can work together.
我们可以一起工作。
To get what we both want
为了得到我们都想要的
help me...
帮我...
Please forgive me, Master Wooyoung.
请宇阳老师原谅我。
Because I got hit by an arrow
因为我被箭射中了
At the ancestor worship ceremony
在祭祖仪式上
by a shameless assassin
被一个无耻的刺客
My body became weaker and weaker.
我的身体变得越来越虚弱。
When the weather gets cold, my cough won't stop.
天气一冷，我的咳嗽就停不下来。
Take your time, Mistress.
慢慢来，夫人。
-I can't say it yet... -Young Master Wu
-我还不能说...- 吴少爷
Why did you come here?
你为什么来这里？
I drank a lot.
我喝了很多。
Until my head starts hurting
直到我的头开始痛
So he came out for some fresh air.
于是他出来呼吸新鲜空气。
I have to go back now.
我现在得回去了。
Madam, please.
女士，请。
Talk to you later.
我们回聊。
There's nothing to talk about.
没什么可谈的。
Sir, you just heard the entire conversation.
先生，您刚刚 听到了整个谈话。
What if it's not between me and Young Master Woo ?
如果不是我和吴少爷之间呢 ？
what do you think?
你怎么认为？
It's not what you think.
这不是你想的那样。
So tell me.
所以告诉我。
What does "I don't think so" mean?
“我不这么认为”是什么 意思？
I have no intention of harming Mu Yao.
我无意伤害慕瑶。
he told me
他告诉我
He kept his eyes on Mu Yao.
他的目光一直落在慕瑶身上。
But that's his job.
但这是他的工作。
It's not about me.
这与我无关。
I never said I would help him.
我从来没有说过我会帮助他。
Otherwise, I promise, I will let Mu Yao marry him.
不然的话，我保证， 我会让慕瑶嫁给他。
It was just his wish.
这只是他的愿望。
It has nothing to do with me.
这与我无关。
if you don't believe me
如果你不相信我
Ask him.
问他。
Why should we do that?
我们为什么要这样做？
Don't worry about me.
别担心我。
I once said that I just want to live a peaceful life.
我曾经说过，我只想过平静的生活。
without conflict
没有冲突
Therefore we must fight. for who we want
因此我们必须战斗。 为我们想要的人
by myself
我自己
manually or
手动或
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
I do not know either.
我也不知道。
Don’t let Mu Yao suffer again.
不要再让慕瑶受苦了。
why?
为什么？
I've never done that. She was in trouble one way or another.
我从来没有这样做过。 无论如何，她遇到了麻烦。
When there were three men who loved her so much
当三个男人都那么爱她的时候
Come together. We must stay far away.
一起来。我们必须保持距离。
Otherwise they will fight and harm us.
否则他们会攻击并 伤害我们。
Who is it?
是谁？
I know what happened.
我知道发生了什么事。
Take good care of it.
好好照顾它。
I tried making soup. Please cure my hangover for me.
我尝试做汤。 请为我治愈我的宿醉。
Don't worry about me, Brother Mann.
别担心我，曼弟兄。
Can't I attend the festival?
我不能参加音乐节吗？
Why are you in this area?
你为什么在这个地区？
Are you secretly coming to meet your lover?
你是偷偷来见你的爱人吗？
How dare I have a maid like you?
我怎么敢 有你这样的女仆？
slander the woman
诽谤女人
Look how angry you are.
看看你有多生气。
- Was my guess right? - you are...
- 我的猜测正确吗？ - 你是...
We should not waste our time with these people.
我们不应该在这些人身上浪费时间。
Where are you going in such a hurry?
这么着急你要去哪里？
Tell me what type of person I am.
告诉我我是一个什么样的人。
The type with a crooked mind
心思不正的类型
Look at everything from that perspective.
从这个角度看一切事情。
Do you still think?
你还认为吗？
Are there any other hostesses worthy of your respect?
还有其他值得你尊敬的女主人吗？
The people of Huangcheng already knew that.
皇城的人已经知道了。
The old man is indifferent to you.
老人对你漠不关心。
Even if you go and take that arrow
即使你去拿那支箭
Cousin Qian , you always look cheerful.
钱表弟 ，你总是看上去很开朗。
But I feel bad for you.
但我为你感到难过。
Do you think you are a big person? Does it no longer please me?
你以为你是一个大人物吗？ 它不再让我高兴吗？
How dare you come and ignore me?
你怎么敢来不理我？
You've thought too much.
你想太多了。
How dare I do something like that?
我怎么敢做这样的事？
It's just pitiful.
实在是太可怜了。
In vain to see you risking your life
徒劳地看到你冒着生命危险
On this matter, Butler Hua
对于此事，华管家
Maybe that's why you're embarrassed.
也许这就是你感到尴尬的原因。
Otherwise
否则
Why did he suddenly ask about me?
他为什么突然问起我？
“Find the problem yourself.”
“你自己找问题吧。”
It's my fault for making you worry.
都是我的错，让你担心了。
I'm looking at you so quickly, where are you going?
我这么快就看着你，你要去哪里？
I heard that Mr. Jong drinks a lot.
我听说郑先生喝酒很多。
So I made hangover soup.
于是我做了解酒汤。
I've wasted enough time.
我已经浪费足够多的时间了。
So I better go.
所以我最好走了。
Don't get in my way. Nong Ying Chien
别妨碍我。农英健
You were just adamant. You're not going to block me?
你只是态度坚决。 你不打算阻止我吗？
Why did this happen?
为什么会发生这种情况？
I'm blocking your path.
我挡住了你的路
You care deeply about other people.
你非常关心别人。
However, Mr. Yai comes from a noble family.
然而，亚伊先生出身于贵族家庭。
And just the scent can help relieve hangover symptoms.
仅气味就 可以帮助缓解宿醉症状。
You will drink unclean things. How can that be?
你会喝不洁净的东西。 怎么可能？
Hua Qian, what does it mean?
华谦， 这是什么意思？
After all, you were born humble.
毕竟，你生来卑微。
You probably can't. You can promote yourself.
你可能不能。 你可以推销自己。
You are truly serving under a servant.
你确实是在仆人的手下侍奉。
But again, I'm not naive.
但话又说回来，我并不天真。
About treatment using aromatherapy
关于芳香疗法治疗
owner...
所有者...
brother man
兄弟人
Hurry up and get the soup.
赶紧去喝汤吧。
I think it would be better to go before it gets colder.
我觉得趁天气变冷之前走比较好。
- Cousin... - Hua Chen
- 表弟... - 华晨
Have you lost your mind?
你疯了吗？
I'm sorry for saying this.
我很抱歉这么说。
You just made a mistake.
你刚刚犯了一个错误。
Why did you come to punish me?
你为什么要来惩罚我？
You always ignored me.
你总是不理我。
I sent a message to Butler Hua.
我给华管家发了消息。
countless times
无数次
Except you do bad things to me.
除非你对我做坏事。
You also tried to bite your benefactor.
你还试图咬你的恩人。
Do you really want to disobey your father's orders?
你真的想违抗你父亲的命令吗？
I don't understand what you mean.
我不明白你的意思。
Don't come and make a mess.
别过来惹事。
if i don't help
如果我不帮忙
Your father probably won't have a chance to work.
你父亲可能没有机会工作。
I am the deacon here.
我是这里的执事。
You are just an ungrateful person.
你只是一个忘恩负义的人。
Who betrays his benefactor?
谁背叛了自己的恩人？
In the end, you'll have to let me help you.
最后，你必须让我帮你。
Brother, you are saying absolutely nonsense.
兄弟，你这话根本就是胡说八道。
My father was trained. From long ago, my lord.
我父亲受过训练。 从很久以前开始，陛下。
You just worked here.
你刚在这里工作。
Only a few years have passed.
仅仅几年过去了。
Why does that person need your help?
为什么那个人需要你的帮助？
Also, what skills do you have?
另外，你有什么技能？
To take care of the entire Hua family
照顾整个华家
You stupid idiot.
你这个愚蠢的白痴。
But aren’t you so proud that you don’t know?
但你不是很骄傲自己不知道吗？
Do you think Butler Hua does?
你觉得华管家会吗？
Will you bow your head at my feet?
你愿意在我的脚下低下头吗？
He had to rely on me to watch over him. foot movement
他必须依靠我来照顾他。 足部运动
I may not know everything about my father.
我可能并不了解我父亲的一切。
But at least I know him better than you do.
但至少我比你更了解他。
If that person is really ambitious
如果那个人真的有野心
Why are you pretending not to know?
你为什么要假装不知道？
Please ask about the people you sent
请询问您派出的人员
during these months
在这几个月里
You must understand it first.
你必须先理解它。
My father never depended on you.
我父亲从来没有依赖过你。
But it's just the opposite.
但事实恰恰相反。
Is that so?
是这样吗？
You may not know this.
你可能不知道这一点。
But a few days ago
但前几天
Butler Hua took great care of me.
华管家对我非常照顾。
Sending many gifts
送很多礼物
If so, I should tell him this.
如果是这样，我应该告诉他这件事。
severance of family relationships
断绝家庭关系
It's better than risking being misunderstood.
这比冒着被误解的风险要好。
With the intention of giving a gift
出于送礼的目的
You think I need help. So much from him?
你认为我需要帮助。 他就这么多？
without him
没有他
I still managed to get to this point.
我还是设法走到了这一步。
You were watching.
你在看。
soon
很快
I will be the mistress. head family's mansion
我将成为情妇。 一家之主的宅邸
And your whole family must kneel before me
你全家都 必须跪在我面前
“More stupid than ever.”
“比以前更愚蠢了。”
You have the right to decide. Since when did you replace me?
您有权决定。 从什么时候开始你取代了我？
- My lord... - You are just a maid.
- 陛下... - 你只是一个女仆。
Do you plan to appoint yourself as:
您是否打算任命自己为：
The mistress of the Zhong Family Mansion or what?
钟家府的女主人还是什么？
No wonder you aroused my anger. you are...
难怪你激起了我的愤怒。你是...
You haven't answered my question yet.
你还没有回答我的问题。
You are just a maid.
你只是一个女仆。
Butler I showed you mercy because of whoa.
巴特勒 我对你表示怜悯是因为哇。
But I've never thought of that. You must be very ambitious.
但我从来没想过， 你一定很有野心。
No, master...
不，主人...
Butler Hua He forced me to do this.
华河管家 逼我这么做的。
Didn't you just say it yourself?
你刚才不是直接说了吗？
That I don't have to depend on my father in any way.
我不必以任何方式依赖我的父亲。
Why blame him now?
为什么现在要怪罪他呢？
please. Look at the goodness in our family.
请。 看看我们家的善良。
And don't punish my cousin so harshly.
别这么严厉地惩罚我表弟。
I'm too weak to be in this environment
我太弱了， 无法适应这种环境
So you have to ask permission first.
所以你必须先征得许可。
Whore Hua Qian
妓女华谦
be careful.
当心。
government
政府
- Underfoot
- 脚下
Forgive me at your feet.
原谅我在你的脚下。
Madam, are you hurt?
女士，你受伤了吗？
At the teacher's feet...
在老师脚下...
The two women were arrested and imprisoned.
这两名妇女被捕并入狱。
Clear your mouth...
清清你的嘴...
firmly
牢牢
I received it.
我收到了。
Forgive me at your feet.
原谅我在你的脚下。
He went to stay at a nearby house.
他去附近的一所房子住了下来。
please wait for a moment.
请稍等。
I'll get you some clean clothes quickly.
我很快就会给你拿一些干净的衣服。
underfoot...
脚下……
go.
去。
won't you come?
你不来吗？
teacher
老师
Go and meet your mistress.
去见见你的情妇吧。
In case she gets lost
万一她迷路了
I got you.
我接到你了。
likely
可能
too easy
太容易了
I've heard about you for a long time, Grand Master.
我很久以前就听说过您了， 大师。
nice to meet you
很高兴见到你
Real people look even more impressive.
真实的人 看起来更令人印象深刻。
Master Wooyoung, I’m really happy.
佑荣老师，我真的很高兴。
The Maid Grand Master standing next to him.
站在他身边的侍女大人。
So beautiful
如此美丽
Young Master Wu, this was truly a waste of manners.
吴少， 这实在是太失礼了。
Is that true? Then I guess I should apologize.
真的吗？那我想我应该道歉。
But we don't have many rules.
但我们没有太多规则。
So I'm used to doing what I want.
所以我习惯了做自己想做的事。
Send someone to follow at your feet.
派人跟在你脚下。
The festival is almost over.
节日快结束了。
If he's not there, we'll look bad.
如果他不在，我们的处境就会很糟糕。
You, princess.
你，公主。
Go and follow His Majesty.
快去跟随陛下吧。
Have your maid guard outside.
让你的女仆守在外面。
And when Gao Yu arrived, he was invited.
而高宇一到，就受到了邀请。
Therefore, I don't want to go in.
所以，我不想进去。
according to your manners
按照你的举止
Who knows if we both don't say anything?
谁知道我们俩不说话呢？
Or do you want other people to know too?
或者你也想让其他人知道吗？
That I'm in this situation
我处于这种情况
because of you
因为有你
What is that?
那是什么？
Jinhua powder is a painkiller.
金花粉是止痛药。
I was hurt because of you
我因为你而受伤
So you should be the one to apply the medicine to me.
所以你应该是给我上药的人。
My back doesn't touch.
我的背没有碰到。
Have a maid guard the door.
派个女仆把门。
What are you going to do?
你会怎样做？
I'm getting ready to apply the medicine.
我正准备用药。
like that...
像那样...
Let Qianzi help you instead.
让千子来帮你吧。
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
Can you see the shape of the soles of your feet?
你能看到脚底的形状吗？
Then it would be better to wait and have Gao Yu come and help you.
那 还不如等一下，让高宇来帮你。
Huaqian
华谦
if we are slow
如果我们慢
Everyone who came to the festival
所有来参加节日的人
We'll find out we're missing out.
我们会发现我们错过了。
No...
不...
What types of tiles does Hua Man use?
华曼使用什么类型的瓷砖？
Why do you ask?
你为什么要问？
Pitchers have attributes. Good thermal protection.
投手有属性。 良好的热保护。
“The maid next to me”
“我旁边的女仆”
“Be patient.”
“要有耐心。”
“But I didn’t know it would still be this hot.”
“但我不知道它还会这么热。”
“He must have been over-pleased.”
“他一定是太高兴了。”
“Until I can’t stand the heat.”
“直到我受不了热为止。”
Do you think I've become too spoiled?
你是不是觉得我太被宠坏了？
Teacher, don't move.
老师，别动。
I will apply the medicine for you.
我给你上药。
Why do you carry it?
你为什么要带着它？
Please bring some painkillers.
请带一些止痛药。
Doing business is like going to war.
做生意 就像打仗。
It's a good idea to prepare in advance.
提前做好准备是个好主意。
It's done. We invite you to change clothes.
完成。我们邀请您换衣服。
Gao Yu hasn’t brought me any clothes yet.
高宇还没给我带衣服呢。
So I want to go out and wait for him.
所以我想出去等他。
Huaqian
华谦
Now you were only talking about Mu Yao.
现在你说的只是慕瑶。
What are your intentions?
你的意图是什么？
Mu Yao was a very beautiful woman.
慕瑶是一个非常美丽的女人。
Wu Suo Mo also wanted her.
吴所摩也想要她。
I am trying to warn you with good intentions.
我试图善意地警告你。
Why you...
为什么你...
How do you know...
你怎么知道...
If we like someone
如果我们喜欢一个人
It will be expressed through the eyes through which we look.
它将通过我们观看的眼睛来表达。
You see us differently.
你对我们的看法不同。
I can tell because I am a woman.
我可以这么说，因为我是女人。
Of course I saw her.
我当然看到她了。
It's not what you see.
这不是你所看到的。
thank you who just helped me
谢谢 谁刚刚帮助了我
Consider what happened to Hua Man.
想想华曼身上发生了什么。
It is a gift from me.
这是我的礼物。
person with bad intentions
怀有恶意的人
He would not risk his life.
他不会冒生命危险。
My father is old.
我的父亲已经老了。
As for his older brother, he wasn't keen on it.
至于他的哥哥，他却并不热衷。
More than just inheriting my father's position
不仅仅是继承父亲的职位
Therefore, you don't have to suspect my family
所以你不用 怀疑我的家人
from what you said
从你所说的
You only deceived Hwaman. reveals her thoughts
你只是欺骗了华曼。 透露她的想法
For my safety?
为了我的安全？
How many times do I need to convince you?
我需要说服你多少次？
I'll never guess about you again
我再也不会猜测你了
It's not that I don't believe it...
并不是我不相信...
Madam, is Master Zong inside?
夫人，宗爷在里面吗？
Your Majesty , I brought you clothes and medicine.
陛下 ，我给您带来了衣服和药品。
I will apply the medicine.
我会涂药。
There is no need to apply already.
已经不需要申请了。
Madam, what just happened?
女士， 刚才发生了什么？
It's nothing, we've been out for a long time.
没什么， 我们已经出去很久了。
I think it would be best to go back quickly.
我觉得还是赶紧回去比较好。
Mrs. Chao, if you are there again.
赵女士，如果您再来的话。
Learn about today I am afraid...
今天了解一下恐怕...
are you okay.
你还好吗。
Your Majesty will wish it. Please keep that a secret too.
陛下会如愿的。 也请保守秘密。
So don't worry about hiding it.
所以不用担心隐藏它。
Even if other people don’t know
即使其他人不知道
But it was so absurd.
但这太荒谬了。
you applied for that person
你为那个人申请了
I have to help him in that situation .
在这种情况下我必须帮助他 。
I am not ashamed.
我并不感到羞耻。
So don't think too much.
所以别想太多。
“Why did he change his clothes?”
“他为什么要换衣服？”
I don’t think it’s Master Wooyoung.
我不认为这是吴洋老师。
You will be well versed in this.
你将会对此非常精通。
Among all guests
在所有嘉宾中
Only you can answer all the ingredients accurately.
只有您 才能准确回答所有成分。
I wish you luck.
祝你好运。
It's a Zen perfume. Isn't this normal?
这是一款禅宗香水。 这不是很正常吗？
Our answer cannot be wrong.
我们的答案 不会错。
- Yes - That's probably correct.
- 是的 - 这可能是正确的。
you're right. It's actually a Zen scent.
你说得对。其实这是一种禅宗的味道。
But that's not common.
但这并不常见。
We added special ingredients.
我们添加了特殊成分。
What causes incense odor
熏香有异味是什么原因
A little more calm and relaxed
多一点平静和放松
Added Ingredients
添加成分
It is placed on the table in front of everyone.
它被放在每个人面前的桌子上。
It is a wild tea leaf from southern Yunnan Province.
它是产自云南省南部的野生茶叶。
It depends on what you drink.
这取决于你喝什么。
Types used to add incense include:
用于添加香的类型包括：
Tea trees are over a thousand years old.
茶树已有一千多年的历史。
So it has the following properties: Helps improve blood circulation.
所以它具有以下性质： 有助于改善血液循环。
Only those with a pure soul
只有拥有纯洁灵魂的人
So I can answer.
所以我可以回答。
I don't even know the smell
我什至不知道气味
understand
理解
Congratulations, Teacher Wooyoung.
恭喜吴洋老师。
Mr. Jong, thank you for your warm welcome.
郑先生， 感谢您的热情接待。
but...
但...
How much is balsa wood scent worth?
轻木香味值多少钱？
Turns out it wasn't what I wanted.
原来这不是我想要的。
I would like to exchange this award with one person.
我想与一个人交换这个奖品。
If you're okay
如果你没事的话
What is this young Master Wu trying to do?
这位吴少爷到底想做什么？
I do not know
我不知道
But Mr. Zhong rejected the request.
但钟先生拒绝了这一要求。
Look at his Jiayin medicine.
看看他的甲寅药。
If you refuse again
如果你再次拒绝
The Wu family must have been embarrassed.
吴家人肯定很尴尬。
Master Wooyoung, please tell me.
宇阳老师，请告诉我。
Who do you want?
你想要谁？
A maid in a middle-aged house
中年屋里的女佣
What do you say?
你怎么说？
I thought Master Wooyoung was an ambitious person.
我觉得吴洋大师是一个有野心的人。
I want to marry into the head family again.
我想再次嫁入本家。
But he only asked for a maid.
但他只要求一个女仆。
That's it.
就是这样。
When the person answered the question correctly
当对方正确回答问题时
I thought he was good. The scent side is even more serious.
我觉得他很好。 气味方面则更为严重。
So I don't think
所以我不认为
He will turn his gaze to a beautiful woman.
他将目光转向一个美丽的女人。
You have no right to command my servants.
你没有权利指挥我的仆人。
To move freely
自由行动
She was just a housekeeper.
她只是一个管家。
You are too narrow-minded.
你心胸太狭隘了。
Who said she was a maid?
谁说她是婢女了？
She came from the Zhong Family Mansion.
她来自钟家府。
Just like that...
就这样...
So she is my girl.
所以她是我的女孩。
really...
真的...
It's completely ridiculous.
这完全是荒谬的。
- What happened? - That's it.
- 发生了什么？ - 就是这样。
What is he talking about?
他在说什么？
“It’s the same word he used.”
“他用的是同一个词。”
“This is a great opportunity for me.”
“这对我来说是一个很好的机会。”
“I can claim this.”
“我可以主张这一点。”
“That’s why our marriage failed.”
“这就是 我们婚姻失败的原因。”
“And other people probably won’t be embarrassed either.”
“其他人可能也不会感到尴尬。”
“When I finally asked for a divorce.”
“当我最终要求离婚时。”
Is this your girl?
这是你的女孩吗？
And what about the seat next to you?
那么你旁边的座位呢？
What does Mr. Yai mean?
亚先生的意思是什么？
I don't know
我不知道
Deacon Hua, you are doing a great job with this.
华执事， 你在这方面做得很好。
A man had many concubines. This is not considered unusual.
一个男人有很多妾。 这并不被认为是不寻常的。
Qian, my wife has always been generous.
钱，我老婆一向很大方。
So why are you in trouble?
那你为什么有麻烦呢？
Don't disturb me. My story is better.
别打扰我。 我的故事更好。
I received...
我收到了...
I lost my manners.
我失去了礼貌。
Please have a cup of this tea.
请喝杯这茶。
instead of apple
而不是苹果
My daughter was really disappointed.
我女儿真的很失望。
There are a lot of people here.
这里有很多人。
Don't embarrass your sister.
别让你妹妹难堪。
Come to your senses and go home with your mother.
醒悟过来，和妈妈一起回家。
Let's hurry.
咱们快点。
Today the big man went too far.
今天这位大佬太过分了。
I didn't save my wife's face at all.
我根本没有挽回我妻子的面子。
Because there was only one maid.
因为只有一个女仆。
That's it.
就是这样。
The hostess is the daughter of the housekeeper Hua.
女主人是华管家的女儿。
How could she be so embarrassed?
她怎么可以这么尴尬？
Never mind. It's better to stop talking.
没关系。最好别说话了。
Let's take a horse-drawn carriage ride.
我们乘坐马车吧。
Madam, please go.
女士，请走吧。
let's go.
我们走吧。
"Extra Scenes"
“额外场景”
Why during this time? So I didn't see Hua Rongzhou.
为什么是在这段时间呢？ 所以没有看到华容舟。
Why do you want to meet that person?
你为什么想见那个人？
I had underestimated him before.
之前我还是低估了他。
When I competed with him, I lost.
当我和他比赛时，我输了。
Now you are ready.
现在你准备好了。
And I want to beat him.
我想打败他。
Does anyone know where he is?
有谁知道他在哪里？
I myself would like to compete with him.
我本人也想和他竞争。
do not you know?
你不知道吗？
He also kept watch over his mistress's home.
他还看守着情妇的家。
But now I'm serving her and it's like useless.
但现在我为她服务 却毫无用处。
And others are looking for excuses.
而其他人则在寻找借口。
When requesting transfer to another location
当请求转移到另一个地点时
Maybe that person...
也许那个人...
I'm thinking hard too. How to escape
我也在认真思考。 如何逃脱
It's worth it.
这很值得。